LAURA D. HAMILTON

312.523.6340

lauradhamilton@gmail.com www.lauradhamilton.com

SUMMARY

Proven track record of launching new technology businesses and rapidly driving them to profitability. Launched 3 businesses within a 3 year span; two were profitable within 18 months of launch. Experience driving hyper-growth via content marketing, search engine optimization, search engine marketing, email marketing, and offline channels.

Skilled data scientist and software engineer. Deep experience with machine learning techniques such as neural networks and natural language processing. Software skills include web development, database development, and usability.

EXPERIENCE

ADDITIVE ANALYTICS, LLC Glenview, Illinois

CEO and Founder September 2013 – Present

- Developed popular MaternityCompare analytics tool for expectant mothers that was featured in TechCrunch
- Chosen as one of Chicago's hottest healthcare startups in the 1776 Challenge Cup

BAYRU, LLC Morton Grove, Illinois

Fast-growing Russian e-commerce startup.

Head of Analytics March 2011 - August 2013

- Programmed a proprietary analytics engine that compares the company's performance to benchmarks and emails the company performance results on a daily basis
- Built an order-level financial reporting system, which enabled the company to increase gross margins from 19% to 23%
- Developed a real-time web-based analytics dashboard that identifies operations bottlenecks

ENOVA INTERNATIONAL Chicago, Illinois

Fast-growing technology company focused on online financial services.

Senior Manager, Product Management November 2007 – March 2011

- Launched UK installment business on time in September 2010 due to laser-like focus on key issues
 - Led team of 4 developers and 4 tech QA personnel to launch product in 5 months
 - Business ramped to \$10MM revenue run rate within 3 months, with revenue of more than \$50MM in 2012
- Launched Canadian business in October 2009
- Managed two new product managers to independently own their own products within 3 months
- Managed company's expansion efforts into Australia in May 2009
 - Coordinated operational, technical, financial, legal, and marketing aspects of the launch
 - Built technical specifications for complex transactional logic to support brokered lending
- Launched a US-based installment product, actively managing it to profitability within 3 months
 - Identified system bugs based on quantitative analyses and sitting with call center staff

SUSQUEHANNA INTERNATIONAL GROUP Bala Cynwyd, Pennsylvania

One of the largest options trading firm in the world responsible for ~15% of daily listed equity options volume. Assistant Trader June 2006 – September 2007

- Developed a statistical model to predict a hospital's credit score based on financial data
- Aggregated the firm's risk in NDX- related products (options, futures, ETFs and stock baskets)

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO Chicago, Illinois

Bachelor of Arts, double major in Math and Economics June 2006

- Graduated in 3 years with GPA of 3.6/4.0
- National Merit Scholar and SAT of 1590 (800 verbal and 790 math)
- Studied abroad in Paris and Barcelona

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

- Running, rock-climbing, skiing, hiking; most recent hiking experience was in Chamonix, France
- · Blogging about data science, machine learning, web development, and digital marketing at www.lauradhamilton.com